[
    {
        "id":"1",
        "question":"Which type of JavaScript language is ___",
        "options":[
            "Object-Oriented",
            "Object-Based",
            "Assembly-language",
            "High-level"
        ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"Object-Based"
    },
    {
        "id":"2",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following JavaScript code snippet?",
        "options":[
            "error",
            "Sanfoundry_ Javascriptmcq",
            "Undefined",
            "Sanfoundry_Javascriptmcq"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "code":"<p id='demo'></p>\nvar txt1 = 'Sanfoundry_';\nvar txt2 = 'Javascriptmcq';\ndocument.getElementById('demo').innerHTML = txt1 + txt2;",
        "ans_desc":"Sanfoundry_Javascriptmcq"
    },
    {
        "id":"3",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following JavaScript code?",
        "options":[
            "10",
            "50",
            "5",
            "Error"
        ],
        "ans":"1",
        "code":"<p id='demo'></p>\n<script>\nvar js = 10;\njs *= 5;\ndocument.getElementById('demo').innerHTML = js;\n</script>",
        "ans_desc":"50"
    },
    {
        "id":"4",
        "question":"Which one of the following also known as Conditional Expression:",
        "options":[
            "Alternative to if-else",
            "Switch statement",
            "If-then-else statement ",
            "immediate if"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"immediate if"
    },
    {
        "id":"5",
        "question":"In JavaScript the x===y statement implies that:",
        "options":[
            "Both x and y are equal in value, type and reference address as well.",
            "Both are x and y are equal in value only.",
            "Both are equal in the value and data type.",
            "Both are not same at all."],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"Both are equal in the value and data type."
        
    },
    {
        "id":"6",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following JavaScript code?",
        "options":[
            "false", 
            "true", 
            "compilation error",
            "runtime error"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "code":"// JavaScript Comparison Operators\nfunction compare()\n{\n  int num=2;\n  char b=2;\n  if(a==b)\n    return true;\n  else\n    return false;\n}",
        "ans_desc":"true"
       
        
            
    },
    {
        "id":"7",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following JavaScript code?",
        "options":[
            "1, 2, 3, 6, 7, 8", 
            "123", 
            "1,2,3",
            "Error"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "code":"var quiz=[1,2,3];\nvar js=[6,7,8];\nvar result=quiz.concat(js);\ndocument.writeln(result);",
        "ans_desc":"1, 2, 3, 6, 7, 8"
            
    },
    {
        "id":"8",
        "question":"Which of the operator is used to test if a particular property exists or not?",
        "options":[
            "in", 
            "exit", 
            "within",
            "exists"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":"in"
            
    },
    {
        "id":"9",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following JavaScript code?",
        "options":[
            "123246", 
            "246", 
            "123123",
            "Exception"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "code":"var string1 = '123';\nvar intvalue = 123;\nalert( string1 + intvalue );",
        "ans_desc":"123123"
            
    },
    {
        "id":"10",
        "question":"Among the following, which one is a ternary operator?",
        "options":[
            "+",
            ":",
            "-",
            "?:"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"?:"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"11",
        "question":"Which of the following function of the String object returns the character in the string starting at the specified position via the specified number of characters?",
        "options":[
            "slice()",
            "split()",
            "substr()",
            "search()"
        ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"substr()"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"12",
        "question":"Choose the correct snippet from the following to check if the variable 'a' is not equal the 'NULL':",
        "options":[
            "if(a!==null)",
            "if (a!)",
            "if(a!null)",
            "if(a!=null)"],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":"if(a!==null)"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"13",
        "question":"Which one of the following is not considered as 'statement' in the JavaScript?",
        "options":[
            "use strict",
            "debugger",
            "if",
            "with"
        ],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":"use strict"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"14",
        "question":"Which of the following syntax can be used to write 'Hello World' in an alert box?",
        "options":[
            "alertBox('Hello World');",
            "msgBox('Hello World');",
            "alert('Hello World');",
            "msg('Hello World');"
        ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"alert('Hello World');"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"15",
        "question":"Which one of the following keywords is used for defining the function in the JavaScript?",
        "options":[
            "Void",
            "init",
            "main",
            "function"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"function"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"16",
        "question":"In JavaScript, do the functions always return a value?",
        "options":[
            "Yes, functions always returns a value",
            "No, it is not necessary",
            "A number of functions return values by default",
            "some functions do not return any value"
        ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"A number of functions return values by default"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"17",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct JavaScript syntax to access the element using HTML code?",
        "options":[
            "getElement ('availablecourse').innerHTML = 'See the list of availablecourse';",
            "getElementById ('availablecourse').innerHTML = 'See the list of availablecourse';",
            "getId ('availablecourse') = 'See the list of availablecourse';",
            "getElementById ('availablecourse').innerHTML = See the list of availablecourse;"
        ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"getElementById ('availablecourse').innerHTML = 'See the list of availablecourse';"
        
    }


   

    

]